http://www.prairie.edu/about/privacy/

Musicianship
Outdoor Leadership (Explore 1)
Intercultural Studies
Outdoor Leadership (Explore 2)
Workplace Ministry
Pastoral Ministry & Masters of Divinity | Carey Theological College
Musicianship
Outdoor Leadership (Explore 1)
Intercultural Studies
Outdoor Leadership (Explore 2)
Workplace Ministry
Pastoral Ministry & Masters of Divinity | Carey Theological College
1.1 Scope
Prairie employees, including contractors, students and volunteers providing services on behalf of Prairie Bible Institute;Any personal information that identifies an individual, in whatever form or medium (paper, digital, audio-visual, graphic) created or received in the course of carrying out Prairie’s mandated functions and activities, and;All facilities and equipment required to collect, manipulate, transport, transmit, or keep Prairie information.
1.2 Legislative Requirements
The Personal Information Privacy Act (PIPA) (“the Act”) protects the personal information of the public and employees of private sector organizations operating in Alberta. It governs the collection, use and disclosure of personal information by organizations in a manner that recognizes and balances the right of an individual to have his or her personal information protected, and the need of an organization to collect, use or disclose personal information for purposes that are reasonable.Prairie is bound by the requirements of this Act and collects, uses or discloses personal information in accordance with its provisions.
1.3 Privacy Principles
Prairie is committed to protecting the privacy of individual employees, students, guardians, alumni, donors and friends. To that end, Prairie is implementing a privacy program to meet the following privacy goals:AccountabilityPrairie is responsible for protecting the confidentiality of personal information in its custody or under its control in compliance with the applicable federal or provincial legislation.Prairie has identified and designated a Privacy Officer to be responsible for implementing the privacy program and ensuring compliance with legislation.OpennessPrairie develops and follows privacy and security policies and practices that are compliant with legislation. Such policies and practices are publicly available.Collection and ConsentPrairie collects personal information only for reasonable purposes and with the consent of the individual or authorized representative, except where otherwise authorized by legislation.Identifying PurposesPrairie identifies the purposes for which personal information is collected.Limited Use, Disclosure and RetentionPrairie uses, discloses and retains personal information for purposes consistent with the purpose for which it was collected. Use and disclosure for other purposes is by consent of the individual or as authorized by legislation.AccuracyPrairie makes all reasonable efforts to ensure that personal information collected, used or disclosed by or on behalf of Prairie Bible Institute is accurate and complete.SafeguardsPrairie protects personal information in its custody or control by deploying security measures and practices to prevent unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification, disposal or destruction.Right of AccessIndividuals have the right to access information about them at Prairie, subject only to limited and specific exceptions. Individuals who believe there is an error or omission in their personal information have a right to request correction or amendment of the information.Compliance ChallengesIndividuals are encouraged to bring any concerns or issues regarding privacy at Prairie to the Privacy Officer for discussion and response (privacy@prairie.edu or 1.800.661.2425). Individuals may appeal to the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Alberta to review or investigate Prairie’s right of access or correction responses, or any policies or practices they feel are not in compliance with legislative requirements.
Subscribe for Updates
Subscribe to keep up to date with what is happening at Prairie. We email our alumni and friends a few times a month, and you can unsubscribe any time!
Helpful Links
Finances & Aid
Admissions
Populi Login
Brightspace Campus/Hyflex
Brightspace Online Ed
Library
Registrar’s Office
Youtube
2020 © Prairie College.
All rights reserved | Privacy Policy
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish. Privacy Policy AcceptPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
Populi Log In
Programs
Admissions
Student Life
About
News & Events
Athletics
Alumni
Certificate in Bible (Encounter)
Certificate in Bible (Encounter)
*New Program: Master of Leadership in Global Christian Education
Menu
*New Program: Master of Leadership in Global Christian Education
Bible & Theology
Certificate in Bible (Encounter)
Certificate in Bible (Encounter)
*New Program: Master of Leadership in Global Christian Education
Menu
*New Program: Master of Leadership in Global Christian Education
